CINDY MASTRY: Once you've mastered the revolved triangle pose, you can take this pose to a little bit deeper level by placing the block on the outside of the foot, rather, the inside of the foot.
Faith is going to help me demonstrate that now.
So she's going to find her long spine.
It's always important to find your long spine first.
And she's going to step her foot forward, just a couple of feet forward, not too far. Good. And she's going to take her left hand to her left hip.
She's going to extend up through her right hand and lengthen out through her torso.
As she exhales, she reaches out and forward keeping the length through both side bodies and then she's going to bring that block down to the pinkie toe side of her foot.
A little bit more twist is involved, a little bit more massage for your abdominal muscles.
Again, she's going to rotate her shoulder and her hip open.
Good.
Keeping the hips square.
And then when she's ready, she can extend her arm up to the sky.
Good.
Pressing down into the block and reaching up through her finger tips.
She wants to reach the crown of her head forward and then allow her face to rotate.
You can look up to the hand but if that gives you a little more of a balance problem, then you can just look forward or down.
You want to have your neck comfortable and you want to be able to hold this pose in a position where you can inhale and breathe your spine long; and exhale, sink into the pose, allowing your hips, allowing your low spine and your pelvis to open, allowing your heart to open and your chest to open.